Now, we're called over the regular scheduled meeting of my Majesty to Council for Monday, August 1st, 2022.
Public input or unscheduled personal appearances.
We have Mike Scribo, but I do not see him.
So we're going to Elden Johnson flags on the holidays.
For the last three years, we posted flags on federal holidays from the 80 to 10 times a year.
We're up to about 500 flags posted right now.
And our main objective right now is to post flags, which he wants to lower,
to 50 million on both sides of the street.
A few more donations we should be able to cover to 100% right now.
We've got about maybe 80 to 85 percent.
What I like to do is, if you're off the pass on to your department, he is somebody that would want
to volunteer to maybe come down to the flag bar.
We get five feet and 15 flags that they be posted in the help of the field in Main Street.
And about now we're going to come to again in this being those groups.
These are one of our longer drivers.
We know that we're shorthanded.
There was a while we get a few worst gouts, girls gouts, and some of the people out here calling,
but they're not being insisted on having a short hand.
Our nation is second to the field.
If we get some of your people to volunteer to have a pick up, come down and get whatever number
of flags they won't be able to post.
Just put on any holy up button now.
We need to read a range of.
We can do that piece and that's right now.
We'll pretty sure get this worked both of the flags.
Is there enough holes drilled?
Why not we talked about that before?
I will.
Everything can come with the theater.
No more peace find.
I know it's coming out and check the holes there.
They enter from the first avenue to central home.
We have that street.
I was probably, I don't know if we got 50 feet there.
That doesn't have a hole.
We can get something real.
It's a close to like it.
From the easy hole on the inside.
Real one on the left side, sort of like the shirt.
It'll be sped.
And that's how to deal that one.
New scene.
On the sidewalks.
But we still need.
I promise I didn't mean to get 50 holes.
I haven't checked down on South Maine.
Now they got because most of that is covered with security bay.
And all the other, you know, their own first ensemble to the first.
There's not any businesses in there.
It's all empty-out.
Any buildings.
Right?
So there's not any people that's subscribed to the program.
There's two.
I like the first nationalite.
And six weeks later, it's all doing that block.
Since the work should be run out.
And so we're just, we're needed to go to the bottom.
I feel the incentive at last time.
I might be either to in place.
I have a few extra.
But we're right now.
We're focused.
five percent in whatever percent of the people and fewer donations, why should be recovered
within the next couple of minutes.
So as a council and mayor, you ask for help from employees and we can't give that directive
to employees, but City Manager Boa Rees can, so he would probably be your contact for that
with the barbed heads and who's the staff's revolve here or something, you know, somebody
can be on the health field in the blanks.
I said we're up to the post five, but are now in residential and in the business area.
And one of the things we've got to be, actually, is that we've got to be a sign in our
northwest part of our lives.
We've got to realize more of the industrial housing and coming from these, I'm going
to get a better cohort of the cancer, or sign because of the big tree there.
And we was wondering, yep, if the City could get it down, or should be as busy as we
are, the staff said it's got a damn, we need to have that tree taken down, so the sign
will be visible from the east.
Again, I think that's a Mr. Rees question, thank you, wrote it down, so I did.
The property is the tree you're on, it's on the baseline, it's on the, you know, that the business
park out there.
I know when I was working for the senior center, we've also boarded the business, who was responsible
for replacing the boards, if the people with the bill in the business level, replace them.
And I don't find that anyway, I was wondering, where is one, the City is responsible for that
or if we can, they can cut the tree down, I'm sure we can find out all of yours, nothing to take
down what we just need to take them down, so we just need to sign for that release.
Mr. Johnson, I think this is a fantastic program, and it obviously makes our downtown look
beautiful and extremely patriotic and it's something we should, so I certainly want to reach
out, ask for more volunteers from City employees, but citizens alike, we need to rally together
and see if we can find the volunteers needed and the donations.
We're still taking donations like some people will take in and subscribe to our blank phone ring,
you know, give us a million other donations, we'll have to give it a dollar, but in the box, which
out, because our flags as far as our poles went up from $10 billion, we're going to do
dollar, we're going to do dollar, we're going to do $19, or $23,000, or we're going to do $30,000.
We're going to cost about $50.
And at full same flag, replace this, that's what we need to know.
But you know, however, I hold real good, like I said now we're at, that 80 of that machine with
media in the Government's military opposition.
So we just need to rally together and get it completed.
like to me. On your, I know I'm on your subscribers and it's hard for me to pay you because
you guys only do check or cash, right? Yeah. Yeah. And I'll never have either one. I wish
you the card. Is there a way you guys can set up an online deal where people could pay online
to the card? Because I think you would probably get better donations that way. I don't know.
And this is where I set up like that. I have a share of the finance also. You see if there's
a, I wonder if one of the banks might host a merchant account for for your benefit. I'd
be surprised if they wouldn't. Is that I think if we put it out there where people could
donate online, that you would probably get a lot more donations. Thank you. Thank you. Thanks for coming.
I guess Mr. Screewood, I'm not going to make it so it doesn't move on.
Three consent agenda staff recommends we approve items four and five.
So moved. All right.
Six presentation from the lead agency. Mr. Rebecca Jim.
Just barely. These are also in your packet. So I just wanted to talk about a few things.
But we just basically, um, let me get a little bit of everything that we have on your
volume and flooding of the rises of the toxins that we have to talk to for the superfights
side and the residents that you built have to build one toxic, and I would like to talk more with you
that that. But it's also, you know, one of the lines is when it came to a thing that some properties
can.
and encouraging more people, I would hope that
I felt testifying, they could be removed,
and dealt in a driveway that may precipitate
a chance to, recently, sit out the veil of duplicity.
In 2011, they were posting in,
this is your last chance, extended them with,
they've been to continue as long as it is,
to call it in, that work will be to this proposal
to raise the level of self-adjusting
and raise the level.
It is successful, whoever is, as you know,
I was really impressed with, into the city,
out to the, uh, here, the path,
uh, in the pitch, which was pretty helpful,
was for citizens and children,
there were issues of the environment,
and the bio was for us, saying,
to start from the second bio,
you all have had thought there's been no crimes,
but for the citizens in the fight of the environment,
They, how they would, so our goals are to continue to do an outreach program
expansion.
One of the things that we did this morning was removed from my desk, and to do that
a survey, a walking survey, and that areas in this community, here at the first time that
what we find real share, what we say, no secrets, to share with you, none of them are there.
We provide surveys, we have additional questions related to that we could do that.
The efforts of partners that we're working with right now, we're working with CM College,
HQ and the private group of change, and we're working on a flood increase of left-right managers
and discuss it, which is showing that we have not registered to the public.
We still have a map map that can add additional players.
If there's an additional layer, you all may need a grant to let you have a look at, we want
a renewal of releases to flash drives that have the link on it, also, who people that don't have,
who have basically a slideshow of what's on there, so there.
individuals in public click on a particular quadrant of the county.
They particular quadrant and seek where they are, in short,
what we've got in the layers of that show of it.
But the agents that involved in the background,
were working on a rural, rural, rural survey,
in this corner of the whole state.
Plus, it's to the super fun side.
There are wells that are changed.
The blue and the sinks that you move.
And so, I'm working in the Health Service City.
During the survey to find out,
who in that region, who's in here,
because in the wells,
who's not even the survey,
design that would join the climate crisis,
who are dealing with things that we're also working
continuing the work with the hardest work design.
And, you know,
what somebody did,
she'd think about,
there is a support for an initial return in.
It was too fast turnaround from the wall.
But we did,
we did get late letters.
We got a late letter from the City of Commerce
and a late letter comes in and she'll be,
but that particular grant,
I really like to tell you what,
what sector we were able to get.
It would be talking with city officials,
getting all of our hopes things to get.
And we know we need places.
So that is to allow us to.
to have the other things we're working on, we're developing the stream teams to try to create working with crews.
In person, it's partially in control this year, but it's held in, you know, national environmental community.
It's a wider, and then what I hate about the 1980s and their communities, seeing this whole side.
If you're so moved, it would be cool to write a letter to any one of those things.
Well, thank you.
I'll pay you later.
So with everything that Miss Jim has presented today, I would like your approval to work with her to create a letter that would be support, a letter of support from the city in this particular initiative.
And it's just a letter showing our support in what they're doing in this surrounding communities, in what they can do with these particular grants.
So that's something we need to vote on now, or what I've been on a future, or we just all get moved thumbs up, or normally I would say no.
But there's no financial exchange.
I don't see a problem about rising into work.
I guess the question is not anyone that issue with that or whether you're about okay with that
I'll make that motion
No motion
You have a consensus that was good enough for me. Thank you everybody's not the idea. All right
Thank you
Thank you Mister
I'm seven ordinance 2022 dashed in adding section six dash one hundred
Utilization of copper conductors to the article three electric chapter six of the ordinance and
Travis Jones
Big weekend
Now we're here
About the discussion of the utilization of copper conductors
Kind of over that again
National 17 natural electric code and you see
Stamilers to safeguard
Tenants our fires and with that being said
The reason we're asking
Reinsert the ordinance because when we've revised the ones mistake
Section that we have been said
Place just because
Again, like I said I went through we go
Several
All the towns and a lot of them
That said last week. I think you give more house fires with a little and then you do the copper
It's kind of bouncing
discussion off some local contractor
I'm going to ask our fire chief if you have an opinion on this.
I'll second.
I'm going to.
I don't want to.
I.
Each step.
Parker.
I.
And number eight is the emergency clause for the same ordinance.
Twenty.
Twenty that or twenty twenty two dash ten and that we just put this in the fact immediately.
Is that correct?
No, I'll make a motion to prove that.
Second.
I.
Nine.
This is the same thing we had in the.
I miss you.
A word of six month contract after review of all bids missions.
For the concrete material C 22 dash 39 concrete.
San C 22 dash 40 an aggregate rock C 22 dash 38.
Authorized city manager is Disney.
We're see.
Say.
He said.
I.
So four five.
Davis.
I.
Ten.
Olson associate master service agreement for work order.
Number twenty twenty two dash two for chism spring subdivision.
Platt review.
Not to exceed fifty thousand.
So this is a.
Brings class that we received.
You.
But we'll pick next step to.
The license engineer.
The grant plans.
Hydrology plans.
And then take our results.
They send us.
We're at a point right now that.
Is time.
Those are the only.
Plats.
You received.
So.
So question for you.
This for the chism springs subdivision.
Plats.
If we go ahead and do this.
And then chism springs and up being somewhere else.
And someone else moved to this area.
I want to do it.
Do we have to do it again.
The plan hasn't been accepted yet.
So they may have.
The plan.
Yeah.
They.
The.
Definitely should be there.
The problem we have is the.
The more weight passed.
.
They've gone as far as they could go.
Is that a whole stick without bringing me in more specialists?
We've kind of had it on hold because there's the issue of whether or not this is actually
going to go forward or not, but we're really out of time that's been presented to us.
I'd answer your question more directly, Mayor, probably if a hydrologist who looks at this
man, we end up with some other proposal for that property, at least in a basic information
could be used for that, but we can't sit here and tell you it wouldn't be a complete
waste of money.
It depends on what happens, but we have a time restriction that we've actually exceeded.
So since we've already exceeded that time, could we table this to the next meeting, contact
his brains and find out if they're going to move, if they're going to proceed here.
So I don't want to waste this money, if we don't have to.
One of the reasons this was for all of the agendas to try to get somebody to take the next step,
because we're just in mind, but let's just mind being in there, but we can jump off the wall.
I don't know that we want to be the one to take that next step without knowing that they're
going to follow in mind.
But that's fine, we just got to get something to be more aware of.
So if we table it for the next meeting, you mean is somebody contacting them?
I've been in contact with their engineer.
He said he said he said to me some hydrology tests before, and I've asked, so far, he's aware
they're going to proceed with their act.
was, like I said right now, it's just sitting and we told the residents, we had that meeting
out there that we were going to have hydrologists look at what proposals we still have the
same proposal and it's the only proposal we have but we have not yet had a hydrologist
look at it.
So, when you get things moving on to some other proposals, that would be great.
We don't want to waste money.
So, what is there for all of a sudden, he may also have to be?
I do have one, absent in any other development, he has to move forward, he's obligated
to the state and is prepared to do so.
If a thing or two don't happen in the next week-10 day, those things are being pursued and there's multiple folks interested in making that happen,
him included.
But he is obligated, contractually, to move forward and will.
He texted me and talked to me and we likely need to be pursuing something so that we're not flat-footed.
You just said a week to 10 days.
So we'll know about our next meeting.
Well, I mean, this would be my thought.
We certainly can evaluate each step of the way.
You all are proving it simply because it's the ability to execute.
But keeping in mind, there's going to come a point in time at that point in time at which this property owner,
he owns the property outright, has the ability to do construction on it.
He's going to turn around and say, OK, I'm obligated to the state-to-execute here.
I've given the city X amount of time to prepare their stuff and they failed to do so.
And now we're holding him back for meeting his obligations.
We need to be cognizant of that.
Those two weeks, I'm going to have them.
If we all, like, phone calls and just figure out our rat before we move forward, we need to do that.
I don't know the reason.
I'm saying it before today.
I'm saying it doesn't hurt you to approve it today because that doesn't give a,
notice to proceed.
That gives us the ability to proceed.
Even if that becomes the right thing to do.
But this, the decision of where he builds is not within our control.
So if we gave you the ability to proceed, would we get an email saying that's being put in the action or something
if it happens before or next week?
So we'll all know what's happening.
Sure.
Which I think the understanding would be that we'd rest.
He says, yes, I'm going to be forward.
So we're approving it, but we won't do it unless he says yes, I'm proceed.
Keep in mind, we don't know the outcome of this study, which was raised as I understand.
These concerns were raised by the residents of the part of what addition.
And without the outcome of this study, he may not know how he needs to proceed.
I mean, typically, so check it out.
It is.
In the last and simple hydrology test.
I mean, yeah, they have a stamp drawing and engineer, but discussion that, as far as it's gotten
now, there's been a few questions raised on the same set of eyes, the signal of your hydrology test.
Like that.
We've got to take their work forward.
So this is it normal for the city to pay for this not the landowner?
Is that normal procedure?
Well, the landowner
Is there any pay for it?
To do the plans and the report work the life work just we're doing our development on behalf of the citizens and the concerns that they raised who will be in
more precautions
You know we want to take the extra step to make sure that
There are everything
The water is not you pushed on there. Everything will be right. That all that was one of their concerns for sure
And I do want to stress it's not that we haven't done anything we've done as much as we could
with all some
Under of the old contractual relationship, but now that that's changed
We have to do this
If we're going to go further to get the more the greater degree of expertise
This project would call for
For us to be able to do that
Some of that information though might be beneficial down the road depending on a future development
That comes in or another developer he doesn't go
It won't likely they're going to have a different plan if the set of plans and maybe even the houses and maybe less houses or street
It's not going to be the same
Because this has a minute or four to get so the other question is for anybody
There's the money comes from
That's Jill's to part
General administrative
A certain amount of money just for general engineering
be able to be able to do that budget.
Again, we're not touching this unless we find out that.
So the money won't be spent.
Specifically for this south.
So we're not going to do this.
Steady unless he says he's moving forward there.
So all of this, if he says it to go,
but they've been given this.
As far as all of this has gotten, they got a couple of questions
that we can't answer this contract.
I feel better about it.
You said that that was it.
We're not going to spend this money.
Unless Chism Springs says we're going to do this.
Right.
No, we're use simple.
You like that.
I mean, you said that.
I'm like a motion to approve it.
I'll say.
Parker.
He said, simple.
Okay.
David.
I'm staying.
It's so hard.
Okay.
Thank you.
Thank you, Travis.
Well, having any any new business that has risen since the
Posting of this agenda.
12 staff reports.
13 mayor and council community announcements.
And I've got a couple.
First, I received a call today.
From the guy I worked with.
He's from Bartlesville, but he was over here today.
Working.
And he was up a poll.
And he called and said,
We're going to talk to you about your police department.
That's okay.
And he said, I don't like police officers.
And I really have.
He said, okay.
He said, but the reason I'm calling is I was up in the poll.
Working.
And I hear yelling and screaming going on.
And he said, lady comes running down the road to me.
And says, can you please call the police?
Her boyfriend wherever he's beaten up.
So he goes down a poll called police.
And he said, the officer that showed up.
Handled the situation perfectly.
Treated the lady with so much respect.
And he said, I was really impressed with your officer.
And the way he handled the whole situation.
And he said, it's not changed my view on police officers.
Especially in my own.
And he said, I never, he said, you know, I don't like police officers.
And so that officer, I found out.
He didn't know his name, but I called chief and chief checked it out for him, and it was actually officer Sean McDonald.
So, so no surprise there because I've heard that quite a few times about Sean, but in today's times,
and our police officers get such a bad rap about everything, I want to make sure that since I heard this positive from the community that I wanted to spread that.
And this was someone from outside our community that was in visiting that got to see how our officers handled the situation and it was impressed.
So, actually it's sergeant McDonald's sergeant.
And I'm sure that those sergeants are out there.
So, we appreciate him in his efforts.
So, the next one is this weekend, the Heritage Festival, the Main Street, all the city employees,
Amanda and her staff, Robert and his guys.
Everybody from the city was all in board in a great job.
You know, we added to it this year with the barbecue you've took off and chucked and chained it.
Fabulous job with that.
I know those guys were very impressed.
I hope I'll still just run new, but I know both of them met with the guy afterwards.
And he said, you know, we're going to tell you guys, you're going to rank your 110, and tell you guys how you did and stuff.
And they ranked him on the level 11.
So, not bad for your first go out.
We talked a lot of the cooks, and they were impressed.
They were excited about coming back next year already.
They were already talking about bringing other teams with them.
Like, 30 more teams with them.
So, we're going to do something.
Hour-wise down on Main Street, because we're not in a power for 30 more teams.
But the music went well.
We had some regions in town that really enjoyed being back and having that on Main Street.
It was just a good event.
It really was.
And you got a little rain.
It cooled down a little bit, which made it even better.
But all in all, I had a great time this weekend.
And we got to rename some streets to do some honorary stuff, which was nice.
And, you know, having an Admiral Trussler back was kind of cool.
His classmates were here.
So, all in all, I thought it was pretty good weekend.
And, you know, the city staff got to tell your people they did great things.
The volunteers that came in helped have the sponsors.
They just couldn't have gotten done without the city employees.
The volunteers and the sponsors.
So, I appreciate everybody that's invested in this.
It's grown.
The word spreading.
And, it's one of the big events in Oklahoma.
I think people look forward to coming to you.
All right.
It's really cool.
I don't know how they'd judge that food.
Oh, there's not a bad piece of it.
But it's funny, as I said, that bow and eye got some ribs from a guy and we were eating these ribs and both of Egan.
But he wasn't Saturday because he was hammered with the back of the bow and it's not my choice.
But we were like, oh my gosh, he's written it so good.
So yeah, well, we're down there for the wards, the guy gets ninth.
And we're like, there was eight better ribs in that.
You have a kidney.
But Bowzy, I mean, this dude went off the vegan wagon Saturday.
He was eating the barbecue chicken and he said, oh my gosh, it's so good.
He had all over his hands.
We had to stop until he washed his hands.
Yeah, everywhere.
We had to have a friend friend with a girl.
Yeah.
But it was a good time.
And that barbecue cookoff was fun.
And they enjoyed it because they said normally they get stuck in a field.
And they get stuck in a field somewhere.
And we put them right down the middle of our festival in Main Street.
And they really enjoyed that.
And they were, you can see them walking around.
Except when they were cooking.
They were walking down the joint and stuff.
The festival.
I know the one thing that they asked me about adding for next year was once they get to Main Street on a Friday night.
They're stuck.
They can't leave because they're parked and they're getting their stuff set up and cooking.
They asked that we make them breakfast the next morning.
So I thought we can do that.
We can do that.
You can breakfast right after the morning.
Yeah.
But it was a really fun.
But all in all, it was a really fun.
And a lot of, well, one of the guys got it.
One of the reserve grand champion of the barbecue cookoff on the pro side.
He was actually an annual graduate.
And he lives in Kansas.
He now, but he came home.
And he went back to Miami.
And he got the reserve grand champion.
So I'm kind of cool.
I have some of my back like that that was here one time.
And you also mentioned the local home association.
Well.
And so during this, the president of the Oklahoma barbecue association was at this event competing.
He started to talk to us about adding us to their tour.
So we may have a, we may have to have another level at some point in the year.
I'm not sure.
You like to lean or wear and all that.
But it's kind of cool when you start doing stuff like this.
And people notice how you do it.
And of course, I'm not taking credit for it.
Just showing them the Chuck bull that off.
But a lot of it was how they were treated here as a whole viral community that they enjoyed.
So Kudos to everybody for that.
Pink Kudos to not only Chuck, who carried the torch for quite a while.
I'm preparing for the barbecue with Shannon, who then also came and picked it up.
And not only did that with the barbecue, but then hosted him seed the entire event.
It doesn't incredible job.
Well, this kind of happened if we had.
And I've done the work a year ago, right?
We had to do that work a year ago.
And the shape of it started out as a year ago.
You know, it really seemed like a high-end sky, pipe dream thing.
And apparently, they made it happen.
But we do have to work on that new ordinance.
No issue hats on my street.
But it's already great.
We were telling you, we were telling you,
we were teasing Shannon, and he couldn't wear that hat on my street.
You know, he wore that hat, and I'm sure.
So I think that's all I have for tonight.
Anybody else out here?
I do.
But all right.
You all have become accustomed to me having comments
in one way or another.
Tonight, I'll be slightly more forward into the point.
And as I begin, I want to formally ask Bob Blass,
this council and Ben, to do everything in your collective power
to annex everything from Elm Street East,
to an including anything on 69A,
where our investment of all these dollars on utility extensions
could at some point produce revenue for this city.
Additionally, I would like to work,
like you to work on, and consider this same thing,
for everything a mile north, or excuse me, a quarter mile north,
and a quarter mile south of Highway TN,
East, all the way to Shawnee, Grocery.
And the cool part of this is that you can blame it all on me.
Facts as of today, I have two junior daughters at the high school,
and I won't miss any event of theirs over this last two years
of their school lives.
About 13 years ago, I was spent the summer working
trying to figure out a way how to start any old real-ty group.
It became reality on April 1, 2010.
Today, we are working on a transition,
working to transition any old real-ty group
to a relationship with Keller Williams.
We will be setting up shop in the old school board office in Miami,
which we bought last week, and hopefully we'll be functional there
between September 1st and September 15th.
Due to these facts, I will be stepping away from this role tonight.
I do want to share some thoughts with you as I depart though.
This council works very, very hard to get it right as often as they can.
There are a great group of guys that really care about the Hawaii,
and making sure that things are correct for the citizens.
My respect for the department has and staff has grown considerably over the last four years,
and I believe that you are really trying.
My concern lies, if I have one, my concern lies with the difference between the private sector
and institutional mentalities.
Jill smiles at me because we've had this conversation.
Summer willing to press on and get things done.
on and some, hopefully unintentionally,
or building roadblocks that further bogged down the system.
I don't remember all the details,
but I remember that six to seven years ago,
Dean, along with 20 plus citizens, spent many meetings,
and something over a year,
putting together some type of comprehensive plan
that has hardly seen the light of day,
other than maybe some work in the cultural district,
and getting mainstream on the right track.
Most such plans limit productivity,
me being a private sector and self-employed guy,
it's always going to be my view of government.
But, and they are often out of date by the time,
they get the last eye dotted in T-crossed.
I can think of at least one time over these past few months
where the council did provide a directive,
and we're still six, eight weeks down the calendar from that,
and nothing has been done to push it on any further.
A missed opportunity, in my opinion.
This is no disrespect to the rest of you,
but I have really, really, really enjoyed working with Tyler
and Amanda, because every time I've gone to them
to get something done, they found ways to make it happen
as opposed to any kind of bureaucratic reason why we couldn't.
And I want to commend them for that.
All of you, please know that, as I leave,
that I mean everything I've said this evening, and before,
and I've thoroughly enjoyed working with you to help affect change.
I believe we all have a responsibility to leave things,
better than we found them, and I hope you will embrace that as well.
Thank you for putting up with me for,
I think around four years, and I wish you the very best.
With that, I want to thank David for his time that he served.
This council is not an easy place to serve sometimes,
because we don't hear the positive very often.
We hear a lot of the negative, and we don't get paid anything for it.
We do it because we love our community.
I know David loves our community, and so I appreciate the time
that I've ever eaten, put in away from his work, away from his family,
to assist us, and try to move us forward.
Thank you.
I want to thank you also for what you've done.
You've kind of guided me in ways that and pushed me a little bit,
and I really appreciate it.
I still have your number.
Yes, yes.
I appreciate you two day, but I'm not here forever, but just not that whole time, like
a new year, a long time ago, and then I got through a new year, and I'm thankful for getting
to know you and your family, and appreciate the perspectives you bring, and the desire you
have to see us succeed.
Thank you.
The first straightened thing to me as a private sector and self-employed guy who loves
risk and the gamble, because with failure comes the lessons that you need to get better.
I've always thought that government took out all the growth opportunities because they
insulated themselves with so many rules that they couldn't ever fail, so they couldn't
learn anything.
But that's just me.
But you're all our special bunch of folks, and I think there's a collective of you
in there somewhere, if you just let it out, that want to be more aggressive.
It would bother being a lot, and maybe the NGO, any of my bother our risk guy, depending
on how aggressive we got, but out on the street, the citizens are well aware that this council
with your support has changed some things over this last two or three years.
They get it.
They see it.
It's not the same, and I hope that it doesn't ever become the same again, and I trust.
These guys, and whoever becomes to occupy this seat, we'll keep the pressure on you all and
the pressure on Mr. East.
I'm going to be urging them to do so.
Sometimes he'll turn it over to me and I'll get to talk.
But oh wait.
No, they just will talk.
I'm still council-tied.
Hold on.
I'm going to be.
I'm down.
Thank you.
Enjoy it all.
So we're down now, so Mr. East can speak.
Go ahead.
All right.
I reserved the ratchet.
Interrupted.
Yeah, I'm so angry.
We'll like the council.
It's sincerely appreciate all that you've done the time and energy and effort.
You've put into this the passion that you have for this city comes through in just the amount of effort you put into it.
You put a lot of thought into everything that you do, and for that I'm grateful.
You also listen.
We've had many, many good discussions.
And for that I am very grateful.
As you know, I've spent a lot of time in what you call bureaucracy and getting the wheels to turn can be challenging.
But it takes.
both sides, and that's why I greatly respect your opinions and decisions in the amount of effort
that you put into applying that as a force multiplier to move things forward. And sometimes
that's what we need. But it takes both sides, and that's why I'm glad that we're here and we
have folks that are watching things so intently making sure that we don't misstep and end up
taking inadvertently due steps back. But we have to continue to apply pressure to move forward
because if not, our momentum will spin us backwards. So with that, I hope that we all continue to
push forward evaluating and letting those of us who do proceed with caution to be the
maybe the ones that do pump the brakes once in a while but are willing to let go and steer
and watch all the great things happen. Because there have been a lot of great things that have happened
under the oversight of all you guys. And I think it's a fantastic group that we have and
David, you will be missed. It will be tough, tough seat to feel. So I appreciate all you've done.
I appreciate you. I think I can be more aggressive. Not in this chair.
Three, three, three, two, one.
I agree. With that, all I wanted to mention is a wrap up Mr. Mayer. I certainly agree with all of your
comments around the festival, all in all the weather. I don't know how we did that, but to have
it be a thousand degrees for so long. Perfect weather than one small rainstorm that came through and
we touched it. But then the heat's going to crank right back up. So that was like hitting a bull's eye
on a target. A dart board from 30 feet away. But it was fantastic and a huge thanks to all of our sponsors
and certainly our tribes who, you know, we call this our heritage fest for a reason. And we've reached
out to them and really hoped for their not only support financially, their tremendous at making this happen.
We couldn't do it without them. But their presence was just inspiring.
Them participating in the opening ceremonies like they did this year. We had 10 tribal flags.
Up in front of the stage, most of them represented in person with either the chief or second chief
of that tribe was just incredible. And I certainly want to thank them for all of their efforts and the
support they've given us over the last two years to turn this into what it is. And I know they'll help make it.
and even greater in the future.
And a big thanks to all of our staff.
I mean, guys, that was tremendous.
All the effort that went into that.
It is amazing what goes on behind the scenes
and what goes on from midnight to three in the morning,
just keeping it moving, getting things cleaned up ready
for the next day and then getting mainstream
backed, cleaned up for our citizens
and for the businesses come Monday morning.
It's a tremendous amount of effort.
But it's a great event.
And it's good to see the families come out
and get to enjoy their mainstream in that way.
It's really exciting.
I had a lot of great feedback from people.
I actually had a guy that was who I was bow and eye.
And said, this brings back the feeling
and you have the sidewalk sales.
And that's what we talked about that several times
until the beginning of this.
That's kind of what we want to bring back.
It's a little different, but that view.
Yeah.
Certainly, that's part of one of my greatest memories
growing up is the sidewalk selling.
As a kid, I anticipated that every single year.
I love seeing the families walking up and down make sure.
Really?
Pretty good.
I am 15 adjournment.
So moved.
Sorry.
Please get eyeed.
You want to go?
Hi.